proximic.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Comscore, Inc.

_Effective Date: 20 December 2017_

 **Comscore, Inc. (“Comscore”, “we”, “us” or “our”) interacts with current and prospective clients, investors, and the general public via its Website, comscore.com (“Website”), and its mobile application. This Privacy Policy describes Comscore’s practices as they relate to the collection, use, and disclosure of information gathered from visitors to the Website and application that link to this policy. Comscore operates a number of research panels, each of which is governed by the privacy policy that appears on the Website assigned to that research panel.**

#### What information is collected?  

 **Personal Information**.  Comscore collects Personal Information about you when you choose to provide such information to us. For example, you may provide us with Personal Information when you submit an online form, apply for a job, communicate with us by e-mail, or access client-specific content. This information may include your name; business or personal contact information, such as your address, email address or phone number; and any information that you provide as part of a job application (collectively, “Personal Information”).

 **Data Collected Automatically.   **We automatically collect certain information about your use of our Website and application. This information may include, for example, your IP address, your browser type and version, your device identifier, information about your computer and operating system, the length of your visit and the pages that you viewed on our Website or application. We use cookies and similar technologies to collect this information. We also use cookies and similar technologies for other purposes such as to ensure authorized access to client-specific content, and to track client access to such content. Cookies are pieces of data stored on a user’s hard drive that contain information about a user. Please note that you may be able to view and delete these cookies using the features of your browser; however, deleting cookies may prevent you from being able to use the full functionality of the Website.

Our Website and application also automatically create logs regarding your activity on our Website. These logs may identify the features that you use, the actions that you take, and the information that you access. We generally use this information in statistical and aggregate formats to assess the effectiveness of our Website and application and to better understand your priorities and interests.

 **Information Collected by Third Parties.   **We may permit third parties to use cookies or other technology to collect information about your online and application usage activities across our Website and application and other websites and applications over time for non-advertising purposes such as to help us analyze how visitors use our Website and application. We may use Google’s analytics products to provide these services. To learn more about how these Google products collect and process data and the choices Google may offer to control these activities, you may visit [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). To learn about interest-based advertising activities by third parties on our Website and application, please see the information provided below.

 **Information Collected for Market Research.   **This Website may set tags on your browser that collect data for the ScorecardResearch service, a service offered by Full Circle Studies, Inc. (“Full Circle Studies”) which is also part of the Comscore market research group. You may control your level of participation in ScorecardResearch’s market research programs by visiting here: [http://www.scorecardresearch.com/preferences.aspx.](http://www.scorecardresearch.com/preferences.aspx "ScoreCard Research") We will continue to count the fact that a browser came to a site, but we will not associate that event with your browser. Additionally, if your mobile device platform offers settings to limit data collection for interest-based advertising, you can use these settings to opt out of participating in our market research programs with respect to our data collection from applications on that mobile device.

Please note that this opt-out is cookie based (i.e., a cookie must be on your computer to tell our systems that you have opted-out). If you delete, block or otherwise restrict cookies, this opt-out may not be effective. Additionally, because different computers and different Internet browsers all require their own version of the opt-out cookie, you need to perform this opt-out process on any computer and browsers that you want to be opted-out.

#### How is the collected information used?

We may use the Personal Information that you provide to us to operate and improve our business, including this Website and our application; to communicate with you; to provide you with information or services that you have requested; and for verification purposes. We may use and disclose any information that is aggregated or de-identified so that it does not identify you personally, in our discretion.

#### How is the information disclosed?

Comscore may share your Personal Information as described below:

  * With our vendors, consultants, agents, contractors, and other service providers that we use to support our business;
  * To provide you with any information or services that you request;
  * To respond to subpoenas, court orders, and other legal process, or as otherwise required by law;
  * To exercise Comscore’s legal rights or defend Comscore against legal claims, to enforce our contracts, to investigate, respond to and resolve problems or inquiries (including governmental inquiries), or to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain;
  * In connection with an actual or potential merger, sale, acquisition, assignment, or transfer of all or part of our assets, affiliates, lines of business, or products, including at bankruptcy;
  * With our affiliates, subsidiaries, or parent companies; and
  * With your consent.

#### Third-Party Links and Services

Our Website and application may contain links to third-party websites and applications. We do not control these linked properties and this Privacy Policy does not apply to those properties. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of any third-party online property that you visit before you provide any information to that property’s owner.

#### How to opt out of interest-based advertising

We may partner with third-party companies that may use cookies or other technologies to collect information about your visits to our Website and application and other non-affiliated websites and applications over time, including information about the possible relationships among different browsers and devices, in order to provide you with more relevant advertisements.  

This practice is called interest-based advertising. You may visit [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) to learn more about interest-based advertising and how to opt-out of this form of advertising on your web browser by companies participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) self-regulatory program. If you wish to opt-out of interest based advertising in mobile applications on your device by companies that participate in the DAA’s AppChoices application, you may download that application onto your device and exercise your choice. AppChoices is available at the links below:

You may also be able to limit data collection by third parties across applications by using your mobile device settings. Please note that opting out will not stop advertising from appearing on your browser or mobile device. It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests. Additionally, please note that if you use a different browser or device, erase cookies from your browser, restrict cookies from being used on your browser, or reset your mobile device’s platform advertising ID, you may need to renew your opt-out choices.   

#### Can you review and revise your personal information?

If you are acting as a representative of your company, you can view and modify your company profile information in the client area of our Website. You may also review, update, or request changes to your Personal Information by contacting us using the contact information provided below.

#### Do we collect information about children? 

We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13 years old on this Website or through our application.

#### How will you be notified of changes to this Privacy Policy?

We reserve the right to modify or update this Privacy Policy periodically. If we change our practices with respect to your information, we will notify you by posting a revised Privacy Policy on this Website and accessible from the application, with a new effective date. We encourage you to revisit this Privacy Policy periodically to stay informed about our practices with respect to your information.

#### International Visitors and the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks

If you visit our Websites or participate in our Panels from locations outside of the United States, please note that any information you provide to us through your use of our Websites or your participation in the Panels may be transferred to and processed in countries other than the country from which you accessed our Websites or participated in our Panels, including the United States where our central database is operated. Subject to the next paragraph below, please be aware that the United States, and other countries in which your data may be maintained, may not offer an equivalent level of protection as provided for in your country.

Comscore complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of Personal Information transferred from the European Economic Area and Switzerland to the United States. To learn more, please view our EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Statement. 

 **For individuals located within the European Economic Area (“EEA”):** If you visit our Website or participate in a Panel or a program from locations within the EEA, please review our GDPR Privacy Policy here"). Our GDPR Privacy Policy includes additional information relating to the processing of ‘personal data’ and the exercise of rights under the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679.

#### Whom can you contact if you have additional questions?

If you have questions regarding our Privacy Policy as it relates to your use of this Website or our application, please contact us by email at [privacy@comscore.com](mailto:privacy@comscore.com).
